

Mpumelelo Hlongwane

ID: 8510016038085

Address: Unit 38, 10 Maldives Nossob Street, Winchester Hills, Johannesburg 2097

Phone: 073 441 0007

E-mail: mpumelelohlongwane@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mpumelelo-hlongwane-42b257145/

Objectives

I am blessed to possess an inquisitive and creative mindset which allows me to grasp new concepts promptly and to find unique solutions to everyday issues. I ran an informal product design and development business for more than 4 years, the main activity of the business was taking client needs, conceptualizing, designing and facilitating the manufacturing of a product that would meet these needs within their budget. This involved me analyzing the work that needed to be accomplished, breaking it down and designing a product and facilitating the project of manufacturing it.

This sharpened my critical and conceptual thinking skills, it developed an appreciation for a broad company structures and greatly enhanced my readiness to work within a team. It built in me an internal accountability for deadlines and accuracy.

After reaching the age I set earlier in my life I have reprioritized my career path by take an extended leave from my entrepreneurial pursuit to focus establishing myself in a reputable company and eventually enter and grow in the legal field.

Education

- Higher certificate in Project Management: Msimbi training (current)
- Bachelor of Law Degree: UNISA (Current)
- Higher certificate in Law: UNISA (2016)
- **Certificate in Entrepreneurial development**: Raymond Ackerman Academy for Entrepreneurial development/ University of Johannesburg(2014)
- Matric Institution: The National School of the Arts (2004)

Experience

Common Reporting Standards (CRS) Agent (Team leader's second in charge)(currently)

FNB – Retail & Commercial fulfilment

- Work in various administrative and communications projects
- Presenting FNB products to clients
- Investigate clients complains with FATCA's foreign tax residency requirements

- Contact clients that do not comply and take them through the process up to them being complaint
- Take on special investigations on general topics e.g. how particular campaigns are performing and why.
- As a second in charge I assume the team leaders duties in his absence which includes:
 - Attending morning meetings with the department operations manager
 - Distribute work to the team everyday
 - Keep record of team meetings

Managing Director (2011 -2017)

Msol innovations

- Conceptualized, designed and facilitated manufacturing new products
- Graphic design
- Sourced clients
- General business administration
- One of my products was selected for development by the Technology innovation agency's youth program. This consumed the bulk of the company's time from 2012 to 2014. Please see attached documents (A1 and A2)

General worker (2010 –2011)

Phenomenal Properties (Company closed down)

- Office administration
- Contacting clients
- Typing out office documents e.g. rental mandates, contracts

.

Account Management Consultant (2008 –2010)

Standard Bank (People Serv: 086112 3444))

- Telephonically collect consumer debtor accounts in arrears
- Collecting accounts aged 30 to 60 days in arrears
- Negotiate, capture and follow up on payment arrangements
- Working towards and meeting predetermined collection targets

Skills

- Graphics Design: I have an extensive history in the arts and design
- Computer skills:
 - Microsoft office
 - Including MS Projects
 - o I am a self-taught web developer hobbyist, Languages and Frameworks I can use:
 - Python: Intermediate to advance
 - Django framework: intermediate to advanced
 - JavaScript: Intermediate
 - React

- HTML and CSS
 - Bootstrap
- MySQL
- Graphic Design software: Photoshop, illustrator, Dreamweaver
- Product design and visualization software: Sketch up

Personality Profile

- Very inquisitive, analytical, creative
- Enjoy understanding and interacting with people
- Hold respect as the highest priority
- A humble team player
- I am a fan of humor (at least 3 good belly laugh a week makes it all worth it)
- I am a fan of new information
- I am a fan of innovation
- Driven to succeed

References

• Phemelo Masilo

Position: Learning and development coordinator at FNB in the R & C fulfillment (CRS)

department

Relationship: My mentor at FNB through my project management higher certificate

Contact: 065 871 1298

• Clint Fynn

Position: Team leader at FNB in the R & C fulfillment (CRS) department

Relationship: My team leader

Contact: 076 955 1461

Nonhlanhla Heshu

Position: functional analyst at Wesbank in the ERP financial data warehouse

Relationship: I was part of her Python classes at Wesbank

Contact: 081 499 3848





Head Office: 83 Lois Avenue * cnr Lois Avenue and Atterbury Road * Menlyn * P.O. Box 172 * Pretoria * 0063
Regional Offices: Eastern Cape * Free State * Gauteng * KwaZulu-Natal * Limpopo * Western Cape * Website: www.ita.org.za

Ludrick Barnard
Central University of Technology (CUT_PDTS)
Product Development Technology Station
Private Bag X 20539
Bloemfontein
Free State
9300

19 February 2014

Re: Close of YTIF Project YTIF-00074-CC2 (Eco-baby)

The Eco-baby (YTIF-00074-CC2) was approved for technology development at the CUT technology station. Initial desktop novelty search conducted by patent attorneys indicated that the development of the product will not infringe on any existing patent.

Shortly after the commencement of the technology development, the technology station brought to TIA's attention the contents of European Patent (EU).

Following deliberations between TIA, SABS (Business Coaching Report) and the technology station, TIA has come to the decision to close the project. This decision is based on three main factors which are listed below:

- 1. Project value
- 2. Cost of tooling
- 3. Market implication

Special Projects Unit
Signed by 102/14
Date 19/02/14
Designation (Action) SM

CUT Technology Station
Signed by LUARKK BARNARD
Date 19/2/14
Designation DURACTOL PDTS

Youth Technology Innovation Fund

Signed by Mps Molela ... Hlongware

Date 19 Feb 2014

Designation in the chuentor &



21/02/2017

TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN

This letter serves to confirm that Mr Mpumelelo Hlongwane, ID number 8510016038085; he was a registered student at The Raymond Ackerman Academy of Entrepreneurial Development Program based at the University of Johannesburg (Soweto Campus). He was pursuing a 6 months certificate in Entrepreneurship Development from July to December 2014, which he successfully completed

The programme comprises of classroom activities, group learning and activities in Business Numeracy, Innovation, Marketing, Strategy, Accounting, Human Resource Operations and Life Orientation, as well as entrepreneurial showcases and discovery sessions.

Please do not hesitate to contact the University of Johannesburg on the number listed below or email me on adminraa@uj.ac.za if you have any questions.

Yours sincerely,

Ms Sibongile Thunzini
Programme administrator
University of Johannesburg

Soweto Campus, Potchefstroom old road

Tel: 011 559 5583 Fax: 011 559 5696

E-mail: adminraa@uj.ac.za



2017 -02- 2 1

Centre for Small Business Development (CSDB) Faculty of Management, Soweto Campus







We certify that

MPUMELELO HLONGWANE

having complied with the requirements of the Higher Education Het and the Institutional Statute, was issued with the

HIGHER CERTIFICATE

in Law

at a congregation of the University on 14 October 2016

University Registrar



19875145511209C01411